Prabhjyot Gambhir

Software Engineer

(778)-674-7443 knowprabhjyot@gmail.com https://knowprabhjyot.github.io

Summary

Software Engineer with 4 years of industry experience in developing scalable web applications with an engaging user interface. Specialized in writing clean and modular code and adhered to best practices in the industry. Additionally, a year of experience instructing students and guiding them through fully developed apps.

Industry Experience

April 2021 - October 2021 (Fulltime)

IPD Analytics, Hyderabad - Software Engineer

- Joined IPD Analytics as Software Engineer, was responsible for developing highly scalable web applications using robust technologies and problem solving skills.
- Developed and Delivered Rebates monitor product for drug and financial insights which is company's latest newest analyst driven resource
- Advocated for and introduced better development practices by introducing Redux design,
 CD/CI pipeline for multiple products across the company.
- Gained full ownership and responsibility of products like Rebate Monitor, Clinical Pipeline
 for handling front end architecture. And introduced code reusability and scalability to the
 applications.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and new features to legacy codebase built with Javascript,
 React, Node.js, Mongodb and SQL.
- Additionally migrated from Node.js Server to AWS Lambda serverless architecture.
- Worked in transition from RESTful API architecture to Apollo Federation GraphQL.
- Product Links
 - https://www.ipdanalytics.com/rebate-monitor
 - https://www.ipdanalytics.com/payer-provider-insights

February 2018 - April 2021

Keysight technologies, Gurgaon - R&D Engineer II (Full time)

- Joined the R&D team as R&D Engineer I, was mainly responsible for designing frontend of inhouse products like Switch Manager, Pathwave Project, Pathwave Stations.
- Developed whole Front End architecture and implemented different plugin designs for Pathwave Cloud Platform namely – Test Library, Stations Management and Test operations plugins. Ensured utmost quality design and fully Responsive in two different themes.
- Designed, Developed and successfully delivered Switch Manager to clients like Nokia and Broadcom. Later got promoted to R&D Engineer II

- Developed custom libraries using Angular, React for achieving utmost code reusability.
- Solely responsible for developing the CD/CI pipeline for the products.
- Responsible for transitioning from Monolith Service architecture to Microservice architecture in collaboration to the team.
- Introduced best practices and developed common UI Library called Alloy which contains many reusable components consumed throughout the Pathwave Project by different plugins.
- Product Links
 - https://www.keysight.com/ca/en/product/KS8105A/switch-manager-developme nt-plugin.html
 - o https://www.keysight.com/ca/en/products/software.html

Relevant Experience

September 2022 - PRESENT

Vancouver Community College - CST Instructor (Part time)

- Currently teaching courses like Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js, GraphQL to international Students.
- Developed the course outline for Teaching HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js and Node.js, PWA, React Native.
- Intensely working with students to build their portfolio by making real world Web and Mobile Applications.

October 2021 - PRESENT

Cornerstone College, Vancouver - WMAD Instructor and Developer (Part time)

- Teaching Web and Mobile Development program courses like React.js, Node.js, Javascript
- Helped more than 300 students to graduate and get jobs in Startups and MNCs
- Working with students to deliver Full stack applications with Market standards
- Working with students to develop complex Projects based on PWA, Service Workers.

Skills

- React.js, React Native, Angular
- Node.js, Microservices, Docker, Kubernetes
- Javascript, Typescript, Java
- HTML, CSS, SASS, Material Design, Bootstrap, JQuery
- Devops AWS, Heroku, Linux

Education

May 2021-December 2022

Langara College, Vancouver - Post Degree Diploma in Web and Mobile Development

Guru Gobind Singh University, Delhi- Bachelors in Technology, Computer Science